<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on thoughts</title>
    <link>https://che55er.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://che55er.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>KCDC 2021 Recap</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/kcdc-2021-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/kcdc-2021-recap/</guid>
      <description>These last two days was KCDC in Kansas City. This was my first in-person developer conference since late 2019. While there were still restrictions (wearing masks), it was a fantastic time to see people again. I was able to meet up with past colleagues and discover new people at lunch and through talks, an experience that immediately filled a void in my life. While I have participated in other virtual conferences since the pandemic started, the in-person session was a great experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Diagrams</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/universal-diagrams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/universal-diagrams/</guid>
      <description>Diagraming is a powerful way of communicating ideas to others. In this past year, I have found how much I have missed the time of just working with a group and using a whiteboard to convey our ideas. In the past few months, I have referenced past diagrams or shared recent examples which included a few properties in the diagram that I believe are useful. In this short blog post, I will share some thoughts on the power of diagrams which use simple universal symbols.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHANGELOG: What I&#39;ve Learned</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/changelog-what-ive-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/changelog-what-ive-learned/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year, I shared a communication approach I was trying with my team, called a CHANGELOG. I have been applying this approach for the past six months and have learned a few lessons along the way. This post will recap some of these lessons learned, so it may better inform you the benefits and the costs of applying it.
    Improved 1:1 Conversations A primary reason why I started applying the CHANGELOG, was to simplify the routine need of communicating current topics with team members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide to Meetings: Virtual Edition</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/hitchhikers-guide-to-meetings-virtual-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/hitchhikers-guide-to-meetings-virtual-edition/</guid>
      <description>Two years ago, I worked on a guide that I called the Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Meetings. This guide highlighted many of the lessons I had learned over the years involving meetings at work. I have found having this guide to be a helpful reminder on things to continue to practice with the goal of optimizing time in meetings. With this year&amp;rsquo;s change of virtual meetings being the primary means of engagement, I wanted to make an update to this guide to highlight some of these newer lessons with the virtual format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seek the Second Story</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/seek-the-second-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/seek-the-second-story/</guid>
      <description>I recently listened to a talk that reminded me of some core lessons on how we can view &amp;ldquo;human error,&amp;quot; and how it can help us both with our work and personal lives. From that talk, the content from The Field Guide to Understanding &amp;lsquo;Human Error&amp;rsquo; by Sidney Dekker is referenced. This book continues to grow as the cornerstone reference on building a safety culture. I wanted to share a short blog post as a refresher on this content, and how we can improve our systems by not looking at &amp;ldquo;human error&amp;rdquo; as the cause, but as the symptom of a larger problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Share a CHANGELOG</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/share-a-changelog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/share-a-changelog/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I recently tried a new experiment at work which I&amp;rsquo;m calling &amp;ldquo;The CHANGELOG.&amp;rdquo; My goal with this experiment is to improve the communication within my team and with all the product groups I routinely work with. I thought it would be helpful to share some of my notes here on what and why I decided to do it.
The Name You may be wondering why I&amp;rsquo;m calling this &amp;ldquo;The CHANGELOG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defrag your Calendar</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/defrag-your-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/defrag-your-calendar/</guid>
      <description>Time is a one of your most valuable assets. As engineers grow with their skills and past contributions, they get invited to participate in more meetings within their day. These meetings get scheduled in time slots that show as available on their calendar, or sometimes even when they are already shown as busy - posing as a conflict. This can commonly result in their day being broken down into many different meetings, with small windows of free time on their schedule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QCon San Francisco 2019 Recap</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/qcon-sf-2019-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/qcon-sf-2019-recap/</guid>
      <description>This was my first time attending QCon, and I was really impressed with the quality of the conference. I have been a long time consumer of content on InfoQ, so it was great to be there in person and meet more practitioners that are working on interesting problems. This blog post will be a brief recap of my experience and the notes I took from the talks I attended.
Overview QCon is a conference which organizes its talks into specific tracks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decisions: The Pursuit of Options</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/decisions-the-pursuit-of-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/decisions-the-pursuit-of-options/</guid>
      <description>The Talk Back in June, I gave a talk at Cerner&amp;rsquo;s DevCon conference on decision making, called: Decisions: The Pursuit of Options. The talk has been published on YouTube for your viewing pleasure:
  The Guide Here is the guide that I produced for this talk, which is designed for a 11x17 print-out of the notes that were covered in the slides. You can find the print-out version and references in my Guides section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Novelty Trap</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/novelty-trap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/novelty-trap/</guid>
      <description>This post is the second part of my series that breaks down my guide on decision making. I wanted to briefly share our natural tendency to favor novelty and how that can introduce challenges when assessing technology in our systems. The goal is to ensure we are aware of this attraction, understand its power to feed learning, and to make sure we balance our motivations with safe introductions of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Murphy&#39;s Law</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/power-of-murphys-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/power-of-murphys-law/</guid>
      <description>I recently built a guide on decision making, which included several different elements on how we form ideas and decisions. The purpose of this guide was to highlight common areas that typically cause strain on us humans when we are in the act of technical decision making. I plan to author another series of blog posts, that take each part of this guide, and expand it with some added dialogue. For this first post, I&amp;rsquo;m going focus on Murphy&amp;rsquo;s Law and its influence on our ability to make technical decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualize Progress through Contrast</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/visualize-progress-through-contrast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/visualize-progress-through-contrast/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few weeks, I have been on a hiatus from my normal work at Cerner. During this time, I have been working on several home repair and improvement projects. While I have been doing this work, I was reminded of something that I like to do which helps illustrate progress achieved in projects. In this short post, I will share a few things that I think are important to capture which leverage the power of contrast to highlight progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning with Preschoolers</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/learning-with-preschoolers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/learning-with-preschoolers/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I had the honor of attending a preschool class to share the topic of software development. In order to explain this subject matter, I decided to prepare a few items and have them paired with a theme. I thought it might be worthwhile to share what I used, as it seemed to work well, and I found it exciting to see young minds interested in the topic. Since this was going to be a short exercise (20 minutes of their time), I wanted everything to be simple with no electronic screens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank You Emails</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/thank-you-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/thank-you-emails/</guid>
      <description>Here is a short post on the importance of thanking people, and a common way I achieve this through email. This is also the final part of my trilogy on guidance with email (Email Trilogy blog series).
Throughout our work, we are continuously challenged with newer problems to solve. As we encounter these obstacles, we realize we can&amp;rsquo;t do it alone. Consequently, we routinely ask others for help. In my experience, I found I was often asking other engineers to present in a technical meetup that I was helping organize.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawing 101</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/drawing-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/drawing-101/</guid>
      <description>I previously posted a set of design principles about building presentation slides. In this post, I shared how you can improve the effectiveness of your visual aides, by authoring your own images. This post is going to be a simple starter of how I began including images in my presentations and notes.
Equipment Required For this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;m using the following equipment:
 Dry erase whiteboard and a black marker iPhone (can be pretty old like mine) and using its built in Camera app Preview app on macOS  You can of course use other equipment to do this tutorial, but I wanted to share how I started capturing my images in a very basic way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think Twice Before Emailing</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/think-twice-before-emailing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/think-twice-before-emailing/</guid>
      <description>I previously posted a short set of notes of how I apply my simple process of digesting emails. However, I think there are some other important rules of when to produce email. In this short post, I will share a couple things to keep in mind before you send an email.
Email is where your keystrokes go to die Several years back, I watched this talk by Scott Hanselman on Scaling Yourself, which touches on several topics on how to improve your productivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Principles of the pptx Language</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/design-principles-of-the-pptx-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/design-principles-of-the-pptx-language/</guid>
      <description>The pptx Language A few months ago, I was speaking with a senior member of our engineering leadership team, and he stated that the only language he has been coding in lately, is pptx (referring to the file extension of Microsoft PowerPoint). While this statement was delivered with humor, I found it to be true with many engineers. As they grew with experience, so did the amount of time they spent giving presentations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Let Donuts Taste Like Defects</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/dont-let-donuts-taste-like-defects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/dont-let-donuts-taste-like-defects/</guid>
      <description>Over the course of my engineering career, I have seen and participated in different types of team traditions. Team traditions can help build the identity or brand of a team, which is generally helpful in supporting the overall health of the team. By having a team which has a unique and strong identity, it many times indicates a strong connective bond between the team members. As the lifespan of a team grows over time, traditions can continue to form which further crystalize these unique elements of their identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Large Dog Method: A Path to Creative Thinking</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/large-dog-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/large-dog-method/</guid>
      <description>As I talk with other engineers, I have found a common question that typically arises on &amp;ldquo;How do you make time to stay current on technology?&amp;rdquo; Other flavors of the same question are, &amp;ldquo;What podcasts do you listen to?&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;How do you find technical articles that are good to read?&amp;rdquo; While I seek these same things, I find that many times people do not often talk about how can they optimize how their brain can process the things they have been learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Email Process</title>
      <link>https://che55er.io/post/simple-email-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cchesser@gmail.com (Carl Chesser)</author>
      <guid>https://che55er.io/post/simple-email-process/</guid>
      <description>As I have explored ways to be more productive, I generally find that everyone has a way in which they process their emails. Given that email is such a common element of communication that everyone deals with, and it has been around for a long time, there are generally several different ways of optimizing this continuous amount of content. Here is my process of how I manage my email at work, which I realize is quite simple.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
